(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
必ず導き出すから
Because I'll surely find the way out
ああ　この場所で触れた人の哀しみや喜びがある
Ah, here lie the sorrows and joys of those I've touched
そのひとつひとつが心を震わせる
Each and every one of them makes my heart tremble
ハッとしちゃうほど鮮やかな世界がここにあるんだ
A world so vivid it takes your breath away is here
あなたの無理難題に応えていく毎日に
In these days of answering your impossible demands
アッと言わせるような奇想天外な答え合わせで
With an unexpected solution that leaves all stunned
たどり着いたその先に新しい私が待っているんだ
At the end of this path, a new me is waiting
あの頃は想像もしていない未来が咲き始めている
A future I never imagined is starting to bloom
こんな日々も悪くはないかな
Maybe days like these aren't so bad
ゆらゆらり　ひらひらり　離れ離れ寄添って
Swaying gently, fluttering softly, drifting apart then huddling close
そよぐ風に身を任せ　幽夜に舞う
Entrusting myself to the breeze, dancing in the mysterious night
はい！ということで！今日は皆さん来てくれてありがとう！
Yes! And so! Thank you everyone for coming today!
みんな見てる？見てますか？
Is everyone watching? Are you watching?
ということで見て！今日はこの新衣装なんですよ！
So, look! Today is all about this new outfit!
みんな気づいた？よね。気づいたよね。さすがに。
Did everyone notice? You did, right? You must have.
はい！ということで見てください。
Yes! So please take a look.
このきらびやかな和風の新衣装ですよ！
At this glittering Japanese-style new outfit!
やったー！
Yay!
ということでですね。これは今回、天女衣装となっております。
And so, this time, it's called the "Celestial Maiden" outfit.
傘も合わせて見てください。傘。ちょっと見えるかな？
Please look at the umbrella as well. Can you see it a bit?
これ見て！余のちょっと衣装と同じ柄で今回、新しく作っていただきました！
Look at this! They made it with the same pattern as my outfit!
イエーイ！ありがとうございます。
Yay! Thank you very much.
はい！ということでこの傘以外にもですね。
Yes! And besides this umbrella...
ちょっとこの後新しいアイテムもちょっと出てくるのでそちらも要チェックです！
...some new items will appear later, so keep an eye out for those too!
というわけで！1曲目は「百花繚乱」を歌って踊らせていただきました！
So! For the first song, I sang and danced to "Hyakka Ryoran"!
あのね、ちょっと花の蕾を使ってちょっと新衣装にチェンジさせていただいたんですけど、どうでした？
I used a flower bud to change into this new outfit, but how was it?
どうだった？どうだった？
How was it? How was it?
おお、ありがとうございます、ありがとうございます。可愛いですよね！
Oh, thank you, thank you. It's cute, isn't it?
はい！ということで今回のライブタイトルが「天女繚華」ということで！
Yes! And so, the title of today's live is "Tennyo Ryoran"!
ちょっとこの新衣装チェンジとか、これからのゲストの登場とかで、
With this new outfit change and the guests appearing later...
ちょっとお花を多く使っているので、花が咲き乱れるという意味を込めて
...I'm using a lot of flowers, so with the meaning of flowers blooming in profusion...
今回この「天女繚華」というライブ名にさせていただきました。
...I've named this concert "Tennyo Ryoran."
見てちょっと。ちょっとね後ろにもチラッとお花が見えたり、
Look a bit. You can see a glimpse of flowers in the back too,
余の衣装にもちょっとお花があったりなんだりしているんですけれども。
and there are flowers on my outfit here and there as well.
はい！ということでこの衣装に合わせて今回もステージ新しく作っていただきました！
Yes! So, matching this outfit, they've built a new stage for me this time too!
やったー！
Yay!
え、めっちゃ綺麗じゃない？見て！この桜と、このでっかい月！
Wait, isn't it super beautiful? Look! These cherry blossoms and this huge moon!
このでっかい月とね、この両端に、こっちにもありますけど桜！
This big moon and, on both ends, there are cherry blossoms over here too!
いや、めちゃめちゃ綺麗でしょ。すごいでしょこれ。もうめっちゃ考えました。
I mean, it's incredibly beautiful, right? This is amazing, isn't it? I put a lot of thought into it.
もうめちゃくちゃねちょっと運営さんたちと一緒にお話し合いをしたりとかして、
I had a lot of discussions with the management team and so on,
ご実現していただきました。本当にありがとうございます。
and they made it happen. Thank you so much, really.
ということでこの床にもね、ちょっと、分かります？気づきました？
And so, even on this floor, can you tell? Did you notice?
ちょっとねお花もこの散りばめられていたり、
There are flowers scattered around here too,
余の足元にはね、この梅なのかな？このお花をこうねライトみたいな感じで照らしていただいたり。
and at my feet, are these plum blossoms? They're lit up like lights.
細かくめっちゃ作ってもらってます。ありがとうございます。見ていただきたいなと思っております。
They've made it in such great detail. I'd love for you to take a close look at everything.
まあこのね、まあちょっと気になってますよね、この衣装。
Well, you're probably curious about this outfit, aren't you?
ちょっとみんなで近くで見てもらおうかな。
I think I'll let everyone see it up close.
じゃあちょっと、上からいいですか？カメラさん。あ、ありがとうございます。
So, can we get a shot from above? Camera person. Ah, thank you.
あ、このね、気づきました？このもう髪型からもちょっといつもと違うんですよ。
Ah, did you notice? Even the hairstyle is a bit different from usual.
ちょっとお団子。
A bit of a bun.
まあいつものちょっと3D衣装の雰囲気も残しつつ、
Well, while keeping the vibe of my usual 3D outfit,
残しつつねちょっと新しい髪型にさせていただきました。
...I've gone with a new hairstyle.
そしてそして、ちょっと、じゃあちょっといいですか？
And also, well, could we...?
あ、あら、あら可愛いですよね！
Oh, my, my, it's cute, isn't it!
ららららら〜 このお花
Lalala-lala! This flower...
そう、ステージの各所にも入っている、この梅っぽい花っぽい感じも入れていただきつつ...
It's also in various places on the stage, this plum-blossom feel...
見て！見てください！
Look! Please look at this!
この振袖にもちゃんと付いてます、このお花。
These flowers are properly attached to these furisode sleeves too.
綺麗でしょう？見て、綺麗でしょう？
Isn't it beautiful? Look, beautiful, right?
よかわよでしょう？いいでしょう？
It's so cute, right? Good, right?
はい、ということで、この足元にもちょっと注目していただきたいんですけど...
And now, I'd like you to pay a little attention to my feet...
見て！この草履も新しくなりました！
Look! These zori sandals are also new!
可愛いよね、細いよね、ちょっと袖の色と合わせて。
They're cute and slim, matching the sleeve colors.
こっちは白で、こっちはちょっと茶色っぽい感じになってます。
This one is white, and this one is a brownish color.
そしてね、この衣装すごいところがね...
And the amazing thing about this outfit is...
どんだけ踊ってもですよ、足元見てください。めっちゃ伸びるんです、これ。すごいでしょ！
No matter how much I dance, look! It stretches so much! Amazing, right?
これ、すごくない？これ！どんだけやってもめっちゃ伸びるからね！
Isn't this amazing? No matter what I do, it stretches!
ということで、はい、小ネタでした！ははは！
So, yes, that was a little reveal! Hahaha!
はい、じゃあちょっと、まあこの新しい衣装にもなりましたし、新しいステージにもなったということで...
Now, since I have this new outfit and a new stage...
ちょっと、ちょっと１枚目でもね、ちょっとお写真撮りますか？お写真。
Shall we take a photo? Maybe just one for now.
このせっかくだし、この桜のさ、めっちゃ咲いてるところあるから、ここでちょっと撮ろうよ、撮ろうよ。
Since the cherry blossoms are in full bloom over here, let's take some!
じゃあちょっとカメラさん来てください。こっち、こっち、こっち！
Camera-san, please come over here. This way, this way!
あ、めっちゃ、めっちゃ映える！見て！すごいでしょ、これ！めっちゃ綺麗だよね！
Oh, it's so photogenic! Look! Amazing, right? It's beautiful!
このね、桜の色とかも、めっちゃ決めました。
I really put a lot of thought into the cherry blossom colors.
めっちゃ、あ、でもね、このライブ中にもめちゃめちゃ変わったりするんですよ、ライティングとかもね。
And you know, the lighting and everything will change during the live too.
変わったり雰囲気もまた変わるので、それも含めて見てほしいんですけど...
The atmosphere will be different, so I want you to see that too.
まあちょっとそれを込めて、ここでお写真なんか撮っちゃおうかな！
With all that in mind, I think I'll take some photos here!
みんな、みんなスクショいっぱい撮ってくださいね！みんなハッシュタグ付けて！
Everyone, please take lots of screenshots! Use the hashtag!
たくさんポストしてね！撮ってる？撮れてる？いい感じ？
Post them a lot! Are you getting them? Looking good?
いい感じか？じゃあちょっと傘無しバージョンもちょっとやってみますか。
Looking good? Now, let's try a version without the umbrella.
どう？傘無し。傘無しもちょっと撮れるかしら。
How's this? Without the umbrella. Can you get some of this too?
あ、いいんじゃない？いいんじゃない？あ、撮れてる？
Oh, isn't this great? Oh, are you getting them?
お、めっちゃいいよ、めっちゃいい角度じゃ。お、いいね、いいね、いいね！
Wow, it's really good! That's a great angle. Nice, nice!
へへへ！はい、じゃあということで、お写真はね、これくらいにさせていただきまして。
Hehehe! Alright, let's leave the photos at that for now.
続きはね、ちょっと細かい衣装やら、まあちょっとスクショタイムはメインでね、この後あると思うんで。
There will be a main screenshot time later for the outfit details.
そのあともね、ミニライブとかもありますので、そちらもぜひぜひチェックしていただければなと思います！
After that, we have a mini-live, so please check that out too!
そして、本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
And today's hashtag is this one!
ハッシュタグ #百鬼あやめ7周年新衣装3D で、ちょっとね、長いんですけど...
#NakiriAyame7thAnniversaryNew3DOutfit... it's a bit long, but...
長いんですけど、このたくさん綺麗なこのステージと、この綺麗な衣装をたくさんたくさんスクショして、一緒にポストしてください！
Please take lots of screenshots of this stage and outfit and post them!
はい、ということで、今回は、７周年を兼ねた... え、７周年！？
So, this time is for my 7th anniversary. 7 years!?
ってことは、え、もう７年やってるんですか！？っていう感じなんですけど。
Which means I've been doing this for 7 years now! It feels like that.
今回はその７周年と、新衣装お披露目を兼ねたライブとなっております。
This live is for both the anniversary and the new outfit reveal.
これからね、ゲストもたくさん呼んでいますので、楽しみにしていてください！
I've invited lots of guests, so please look forward to it!
なんと、なんと！最後には特大サプライズもあるので！
And! There's a huge surprise at the very end!
絶対に最後まで見逃さないでね！チャンネルはそのままだよ！
So don't miss anything until the end! Keep the channel right here!
頼むね！はい、じゃあということで！
I'm counting on you! Alright then!
夢の中でも 花が散ってる
Even in my dreams, the flowers are scattering
ひらひら舞う 暗闇に浮かぶ桜
Fluttering, fluttering, the cherry blossoms floating in the darkness
水面に落ちたら 君はもう一度咲くのかな
If they fall on the water surface, will you bloom once more?
ひらひら ひらら
Hira hira hirari
桜月夜に宿る いたずらな風
In the cherry blossom moonlight night, a mischievous wind
匂いだけ残して
Leaving only its scent behind
騒ぎ出す
Everything begins to stir
さよならした
If we say goodbye,
会えないのでしょう
we likely won't meet again...
記憶奪い
Taking my memories,
沈んでいく
it's sinking down.
思い出の破片が剥がれても
Even if the fragments of my memories peel away,
光る鱗で隠すの
I'll hide them with shining scales.
眩いほどに
To a dazzling degree...
美しい
how beautiful.
ひらひらひらら
Fluttering down,
fluttering, fluttering down.
瞼の裏 暗闇に浮かぶ桜
Behind my eyelids, cherry blossoms float in the dark.
水面に落ちたら
If they fall upon the water's surface,
君はもう一度咲くのかな
will you bloom once more?
サヨナラしたら
If we say goodbye,
会えないのでしょう
we likely won't meet again.
言えないままの気持ちだけが
Only these unspoken feelings
花びら浮んだ
floated like petals,
桜の橋になれ
become a bridge of cherry blossoms.
当たり前の景色が
The everyday scenery
ひらひらと舞い
dances down in flutters,
音もなく消えてく
disappearing without a sound.
細い雨に濡れた想いが
Feelings drenched by the fine rain
霞んでゆく
begin to grow hazy.
他の誰かに向けた笑顔を見て
Seeing that smile meant for someone else,
忘れた日は蘇る
the days I'd forgotten come flooding back.
色のない夜を
A colorless night,
染めてく
being stained away.
君と出会った去年の春と
Last spring, when I met you,
同じ場所で同じ景色見つめてた
I gazed at the same scenery in the same place.
咲き誇るほどに痛む
It hurts as much as they are in full bloom,
君がいない桜
the cherry blossoms without you here.
生まれ変わってまた咲くのでしょう
They'll be reborn and bloom again, won't they?
戻れない場所と知りながら
While knowing it's a place I can't return to...
散り行く花びら
petals scatter and fall,
手のひらにのせて
resting upon my palm.
花明かりに誘われて
Enticed by the cherry blossom glow,
胸の中に降り積もる
it piles up deep within my heart.
光と影 舞い散る吹雪の
Light and shadow in a dancing blizzard,
思い出だけ
of only memories,
白く染めてく
staining everything white.
ひらひらひらら
Fluttering down,
fluttering, fluttering down.
瞼の裏 暗闇に浮かぶ桜
Behind my eyelids, cherry blossoms float in the dark.
水面に落ちたら
If they fall upon the water's surface,
君はもう一度咲くのかな
will you bloom once more?
サヨナラしたら
If we say goodbye,
会えないのでしょう
we likely won't meet again.
言えないままの気持ちだけが
Only these unspoken feelings
花びらに変わっても
even if they turn into petals...
君と出会った去年の春と
Last spring, when I met you,
同じ場所で同じ景色見つめてたい
I want to gaze at the same scenery in the same place.
咲き誇るほどに痛む
It hurts as much as they are in full bloom,
君がいない桜
the cherry blossoms without you here.
夢の中でも花が散ってゆく
Even in my dreams, the flowers scatter away.
暗闇に浮かんだ桜が
The cherry blossoms floating in the dark,
水面に落ちたら また会えるのかな
if they fall on the water, can we meet again?
月明かり昇る刻
When the moonlight rises
灯る赤提灯
The red lanterns light up
祭囃子の合図
The signal of the festival music
ふわり 蝶が誘い出す
A butterfly softly lures you out
（ちょいと覗いて見てごらん）
Take a little peek and see
迷い込めば 抜け出せない
Once you wander in, you can't escape
楽しいことがしたいなら
If you want to do something fun
おいでませ極楽浄土
Welcome to the paradise land
歌えや歌え
Sing, oh sing
心のままに
Just as your heart desires
アナタの声を
Let me hear
さあ聞かせて
your voice
踊れや踊れ
Dance, oh dance
時を忘れ
Forget about time
今宵共に
Tonight, together
狂い咲き
Blooming wildly
美しく咲く花も
Even the beautiful blooming flowers
いつか散りゆくもの
Will one day scatter and fall
それならこの一夜を
If that's the case, then this one night
もっと熱く愛したい
I want to love even more passionately
ちょいといいこといたしましょう
Let's do something nice
これは夢か幻か
Is this a dream or an illusion?
嘘も真もない世界
A world with neither lies nor truth
ゆきましょう 極楽浄土
Let's go to the paradise land
歌えや歌え
Sing, oh sing
心のままに
Just as your heart desires
乱れる髪
Your disheveled hair
気にもせずに
Without even a care
踊れや踊れ
Dance, oh dance
時を忘れ
Forget about time
今宵共に
Tonight, together
狂い咲き
Blooming wildly
ちょいといいこといたしましょう
Let's do something nice
嘘も真もない世界
A world with neither lies nor truth
ゆきましょう 極楽浄土
Let's go to the paradise land
歌えや歌え
Sing, oh sing
心のままに
Just as your heart desires
アナタの声を
Let me hear
さあ聞かせて
your voice
踊れや踊れ
Dance, oh dance
時を忘れ
Forget about time
今宵共に
Tonight, together
狂い咲き
Blooming wildly
今宵アナタと
Tonight, with you
狂い咲き
Blooming wildly
許婚きゅん
Fiancé Kyun
どいつもこいつもなんだかやっぱの天気
Everyone and everything, it's the usual forecast
気になるあのこの悩みもきっとあるでしょ
Surely that girl you're interested in has worries too
ざっとで半端な憂鬱ももうはむれ同じ
Even the slight, half-baked melancholy is just part of the herd
あんたの頭の中はぐちゃぐちゃさ
The inside of your head is all messy
ドンマイ弊害いくじのない魔法て意識
Don't mind, it's just a magic consciousness with no side effects
いけないいけない事柄なんてないから
Because there's no such thing as a forbidden matter
イーアルサンスー
One, two, three
じゃんけんぽんで
Rock-paper-scissors
さあおゆ
Let's go
渦中で大パニックででんにみだれて
In the midst of it all, a big panic, wildly disarrayed
きみはもう
You are already
ハイスピードだな
High speed
あーりゃま
Oh my
こりゃま
Goodness
おまちかね
The long-awaited
ハチャでメチャなドラマ
Hectic and messy drama
派手にドラマが
Flashily, the drama
のるよ
Is taking off!
イイイイナズキュン I love you
I-I-I-I-Fiancé Kyun, I love you
なのも24時間
Being yours 24 hours a day
愛もちょうだい
Give me some love too
はて？
Huh?
イイイイいつかバックュン
I-I-I-I-Someday, Bang-Kyun
アイアイアイアイ
I-I-I-I
もう1/2じゃもののたんない
Just 1/2 of you isn't enough
避けてても結局見えないあいつの胸の内
Even if I avoid it, I still can't see into his heart
おじゃまの背伸びも気取りもいらないかな
I don't need pesky showing off or acting cool
先輩後輩ヤンキージャンキー関係ない
Senior, junior, yankee, junkie—it doesn't matter
いざ尋常に勝負
Now, let's have a fair fight
君ともしもその気なら
If you're up for it
Bon meat-za 始まりそうならさ
If it feels like 'Bon meat-za' is starting...
また犬技繰り出す
Unleashing those dog tricks again
僕で
If it's me...
いれば so sweet だな
it'll be so sweet
あれな どこか同じだね
That part's the same somewhere, right?
へちゃむくれな修羅場
A messy, chaotic scene
派手なドラが鳴るよ
A flashy gong will ring out
意味深な like you 曖昧な愛より三球
A meaningful 'like you', better than vague love, thank you
しのぎも言わず愛してちょうだい
Give me your love without hesitation
まじ一世一代 血ブーなのだ
Wait, once in a lifetime, it's a 'blood boo'!
自分の意思はどんなもんじゃい
How strong is your own will?
い・い・い・許婚っきゅん I love you なのだ
E-e-e-Iinazukkyun, I love you indeed!
四六時中愛をちょうだい
Give me love 24/7
さて?
Well?
い・い・一か八ッキュン I・哀・逢・愛
E-e-It-all-or-nothing-kyun, I-sorrow-meeting-love
罠ろっきゅー 1/2がもうたまんない
Trap rock-you, 1/2 is already unbearable
これなんて試練 会いたいかも知れん
Is this a trial? I might want to see you
毎晩必勝 先輩タリナイア
Winning every night, I need more of you, Senpai
前代未聞
Unprecedented,
天真爛漫
innocent and carefree,
変幻無双
matchless transformation,
明鏡止水
clear and serene mind.
せーの
One, two...
いち に さん はい
One, two, three, go!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤー
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha-yah!
さあさあさあ これよりご覧いただけますのは 私たちの栄枯盛衰
Come one, come all! What you're about to see is our ups and downs
時代は常に日進月歩 聞いてて老若男女
The times are always moving forward; listen up, young and old
一見は勧善懲悪 悪者どもを一刀両断
At first glance it's rewarding good and punishing evil, cutting down the villains
「でもホントにそれだけでいいの?」 楽しもう 妄想繚乱
"But is that really enough?" Let's enjoy the wild delusions!
もうなんだってこんにゃく問答
Everything's just a nonsensical debate now
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤー
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha-yah!
よーぽん!
Yo, pon!
どこからともなく現れて すぐにどこかへ行っちゃって
Appearing out of nowhere, and vanishing just as fast
神出鬼没 チャンスを待ったら一進一退
Elusive and fleeting; wait for a chance, and it's a back-and-forth
追いかければ東奔西走
If you chase it, you'll be running all over the place
時代はつねに千変万化 人の心は複雑怪奇
The times are always changing, and human hearts are strange and complex
「でも本気でそんなこと言ってんの?」
"But are you really serious about that?"
もうどうにも満身創痍
I'm already covered in wounds
嗚呼 巡り巡って夜の町
Ah, around and around the night town...
君は合図出し踊りだす
You give the signal and start to dance
はぁ〜
Ah~
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ!
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁散らすように
Like petals scattering beautifully
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ!
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
With my hair disheveled too
一昨日、昨日、 今日と、明日と、明後日と
Day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after
この宴は続く
this banquet continues.
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ!
Dance, sing, spin with all your might!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is Setsugetsuka
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤー
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha-yah!
ねえねえ
Hey, hey...
この世に平安訪れるの 伸るか反るか丁丁発止
Will peace ever come to this world? It's a neck-and-neck, all-or-nothing struggle
強者ども千客万来 ひしめきあう雄割拠
The strong gather in crowds, a fierce rivalry of heroes
乗りかかったら一攫千金 気がついたら絶体絶命
If you're in it, it's all about making a fortune, but you might be in a desperate situation
「でも本音のところどうなってんの?」
"But what's the real story?"
もうまさしく奇想天外
It's truly bizarre and unexpected
嗚呼 たどりたどって夜の町
Ah, searching and searching through the night town...
迷い一つなく踊りだす
Starting to dance without a single doubt
はぁ〜
Ah~
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ!
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁散らすように
Like petals scattering beautifully
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ!
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
With my hair disheveled too
一昨日、昨日、 今日と、明日と、明後日と
Day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after
この宴は続く
this banquet continues.
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ!
Dance, sing, spin with all your might!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is Setsugetsuka
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤー
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha-yah!
花で一つ
One for the flowers,
鳥で二つ
two for the birds,
手打ち鳴らす
clap your hands.
風で三つ
Three for the wind,
鳴呼、月出て四つ
ah, four as the moon rises,
鳴らす鳴らす
make them ring, make them ring.
花で一つ
One for the flowers,
鳥で二つ
two for the birds,
手打ち鳴らす
clap your hands.
風で三つ
Three for the wind,
鳴呼、月出て四つ
ah, four as the moon rises,
鳴らす鳴らす
make them ring, make them ring.
今は
For now,
回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin...
華麗に花弁 散らすように
As if scattering petals gracefully,
回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ
spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin...
髪を振り乱して
with hair wildly flowing.
今日と、明日と、明後日と
Today, tomorrow, and the day after,
この宴は続く
this banquet continues.
踊れ、歌え、一心不乱に回レ！
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart!
今宵は何曜日か
What day of the week is tonight?
水木金？
Wed, Thu, Fri?
土日月火？
Sat, Sun, Mon, Tue?
らっしゃいな
Welcome,
平は成り
the peace is established,
時は来た 正し
the time has come, rightfully.
夢現 夜もすがら
Between dreams and reality all night long.
変わりゆく 事に
Toward the changing things,
恐れなし
there is no fear.
のっぴき ならぬのは御免
I won't accept being stuck.
手まり歌いたい
I want to sing a handball song,
君達が誘う
you all are inviting me.
闇中に後ろ髪を引かれても
Even if pulled back in the darkness,
進むべきなり
I must move forward.
えや えや え
Eya eya e.
はやり すたりの うきよなら
If this is the world of trends and fads,
あしんずる ものはただ
the thing I believe in is only...
君だけと 言わん
only you, I'll say.
通り過ぎ 飲み屋 歌い屋
Passing by bars and karaoke spots,
あんどろ 事などないな この世
nothing like peace exists in this world.
人の世は怨めし
The world of men is resentful,
鉄火はちゃらちゃら
flashy with gambling spirit.
悲し すがた で まじさいで
Truly together in a sad state.
それそれそれそれ
Sore sore sore sore!
今をなげいて
Lamenting the present,
春を待てども
even while waiting for spring,
君の心の うちの
inside your heart,
枯る 涙がわ
the river of tears dries up.
それじゃ叶わん
That won't come true.
どこに行けもめくらめく大名
Wherever I go, a dazzling daimyo,
君を連れて
taking you along.
あまうてなども かたじけなし
Even the sweet rain is gracious,
身勝手なのが世の常か
is selfishness the way of the world?
万物有象
All things in creation,
刻まんと
I shall carve them.
切なきかなとは
How painful it is,
徒然
in tedium.
極楽 巡りあう事
Encountering paradise,
まさに一期一会
truly a once-in-a-lifetime meeting.
酸いも甘いも知れ
Know both the sour and the sweet,
擦れそって この手握って
rubbing shoulders, hold this hand.
生きづらいこと 浮世から
From the world that's hard to live in,
旗を掲げよ
raise the flag,
宵闇が明く
the dusk is breaking.
酔い上がれ 寝れば忘れる
Get drunk on high, if you sleep you'll forget,
昔も今も変わらず 浮世
the floating world, unchanged then or now.
人が嘆かば
If you lament for people,
いつだってちゃらちゃら
it's always flashy.
おかしさ笑って 飽き飽きで
Laugh at the absurdity, tired of it all.
それそれそれそれ
Sore sore sore sore!
留まる春もいて
There's a spring that stays,
雪の日も
and snowy days too.
日出ずるすべての
Everything that the sun rises upon,
輝きを君と見よう
let's see the brilliance with you.
彩る色
The coloring hues,
何処までも
no matter where,
晴天を見晴らしを眺めて
looking out at the clear sky and the view.
受けて花一匁
Receive, Hana Ichimonme,
欲しがる欲しがる欲しがる声
voices wanting, wanting, wanting.
買って選んで 明けないで
Buying, choosing, don't let the dawn break.
猿真似の何番煎じ
Monkey-like repetitive imitations,
満ち足りないない
never satisfied.
未だ進む道半ば
Still halfway along the path forward.
如何なる時も歩を前へ出せ
No matter the time, step forward.
はやり すたりの うきよなら
If this is the world of trends and fads,
あしんずる ものはただ
the thing I believe in is only...
君だけと
only you.
通り騒ぎや 飲み合いたい
Rousing the street, I want to drink together,
あんどろ 事などないな この世
nothing like peace exists in this world.
人の世は怨めし
The world of men is resentful,
鉄火はちゃらちゃら
flashy with gambling spirit.
悲し すがた で まじさいで
Truly together in a sad state.
それそれそれそれ
Sore sore sore sore!
今をなげいて
Lamenting the present,
春を待てども
even while waiting for spring,
君の心の うちの
inside your heart,
涙がわ
the river of tears...
それじゃ叶わん
that won't come true.
めくるめく
Dazzling...
舞台は宵々
...the stage is evening, evening...
君を連れて
...taking you with me.
あまりてなどか人ぞ恋しき
Why does one yearn for others, feeling so excessive?
身勝手なのが世の理か
Is it the logic of this world to be selfish?
移ろうは古今 航路なら堂々
Moving through the route of past and present, grandly,
恐るることなどはあらざらむ
there should be nothing to fear.
寿限無 寿限無 五劫のすりきれ
Jugemu, Jugemu, Five kalpas of friction,
海砂利水魚の 水行末 雲来末 風来末
Sea-gravel water-fish, Where water goes, clouds come, wind comes,
食う寝るところに 住むところ
Where one eats and sleeps, Where one lives,
やぶらこうじのぶらこうじ
Yaburakoji-no-burakoji,
パイポパイポ
Paipo, Paipo,
パイポのシューリンガン
Paipo's Shuringan,
シューリンガンのグーリンダイ
Shuringan's Gurindai,
グーリンダイのポンポコピーのポンポコナの
Gurindai's Ponpokopi, Ponpokona,
長久命の長助
Chokyumei's Chosuke.
ちょーとお時間いただきます
I'll take a little bit of your time.
ご静聴ください
Please listen carefully.
整いました！
I'm ready!
笑うこととかけまして
Talking about laughter...
お祭り野郎と解きます
...is like a festival guy.
その心は？
And the reason is?
どちらもハッピー(法被)になるでしょう
Both will become happy (wearing a happi coat).
お後がよろしいようで
That's all for now.
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう
Laugh, laugh, let's all laugh.
こんな時代こそ笑いましょう
Let's laugh in times like these.
泣いたら負けだ
If you cry, you lose.
やけくそ笑いましょう
Let's laugh recklessly.
波乱万丈 酸いも甘いも
Through ups and downs, bitter and sweet,
乗り越えた あっぱれ日本人
hooray for the Japanese who overcame it all.
笑おう
Let's laugh!
どんな時でも なにくそ笑いましょう
No matter when, let's laugh with all our might.
ぐわっはっは
Guwahahaha!
にょほほ
Nyohoho!
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Don't read the atmosphere, just laugh.
笑顔 笑顔
Smile, smile.
笑う門には福来る
Fortune comes to those who smile.
え〜皆様、今日はようこそおいでいただきました
Um, everyone, thank you for coming today.
ここで一席！
Let's start the show!
ねずみの娘がお嫁に行って、じきに帰ってきたんで
A mouse's daughter got married and came back right away,
ねずみのおかあさんが、大変怒って
so the mother mouse was very angry.
あんな、いいところへ おまえ嫁いで
"You married into such a good place,"
誰が嫌で出てきたんだい？
"who did you dislike so much that you left?"
いいえ、だーれも嫌じゃないんですけど
"No, I didn't dislike anyone, but..."
ご隠居さんがやさしいんで、嫌なの
"the retired master was too kind, that's why I hated it."
やさしいんなら 結構じゃないかえ
"If he's kind, isn't that great?"
でも、猫なで声ですもの
"But he spoke in such a wheedling voice!"
忙しさに身を任せて
Giving yourself over to the busyness...
消えていくなんて
...just to fade away...
べらんめぇ！
Cut the crap!
笑おう 笑おう 笑えなくても
Laugh, laugh, even if you can't laugh,
笑うしかないでしょ 笑いましょう
you have to laugh. Let's laugh!
口角上げて
Lift the corners of your mouth,
ひたすら笑いましょう
and just keep laughing.
応仁の乱 大飢饉さえ
The Onin War, even the Great Famine,
クリアして現代 日本人
Japanese people cleared them to reach the present day.
笑おう
Let's laugh!
未来永劫
For all eternity,
グハハと笑いましょう
let's laugh with a "Guhaha!"
小娘のたわごとと切り捨てないで
Don't just brush it off as a young girl's nonsense.
しかめっつら なんか変な顔
Frowning, what a strange face,
笑顔を見たいから
because I want to see your smile.
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう
Laugh, laugh, let's all laugh.
こんな時代こそ笑いましょう
Let's laugh in times like these.
泣いたら負けだ
If you cry, you lose.
やけくそ笑いましょう
Let's laugh recklessly.
波乱万丈 酸いも甘いも
Through ups and downs, bitter and sweet,
乗り越えた あっぱれ日本人
hooray for the Japanese who overcame it all.
笑おう
Let's laugh!
どんな時でも なにくそ笑いましょう
No matter when, let's laugh with all our might.
ひたすら笑いましょう
Just keep laughing.
ぐわっはっは
Guwahahaha!
にょほほ
Nyohoho!
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Don't read the atmosphere, just laugh.
笑顔！ 笑顔！ 笑顔！
Smile! Smile! Smile!
笑う門には福来たる！
Fortune comes to those who laugh!
誰が弔う
Who mourns?
死地は彼方
The land of death is afar
静寂を破り
Breaking the silence,
芽吹いた夢を
the dreams that budded.
誓え
Swear it,
穿て
pierce through it.
重なる 屍
Upon the piled-up corpses,
高みへ
to the heights...
届くまで
Until it reaches.
唸れ徒花 朽ち果てても進め
Roar, fruitless flowers; move forward even if you rot.
奪わせはしない 尊厳の愚弄に
I won't let them take it, the mockery of dignity.
飢餓を解き放て
Unleash the starvation.
枯れても走ることを命と呼べ
Call the act of running even when withered 'life'.
空に叫ぶ 脱・生存の定義
Shout to the sky, the definition of escape and survival.
骨を斬らせて 闇を断て
Let your bones be cut, and sever the darkness.
傷ひとつ無い 手など愚か
Hands without a single scratch are foolish.
意思も自由も その身を投げて
Throwing away will and freedom, toss your body.
守れ
Protect it.
退くな
Don't back down.
涙も 血も無い 神話を
A myth without tears or blood,
築くまで
until we build it.
燃えろ修羅花 鼓動なき世界で
Burn, asura flowers, in a world without a heartbeat.
摂理に抗い 天命を奮え
Resist providence, exert your destiny.
腐り切り抜けて
Cut through the rot.
心を無くすことが死と知れ
Know that losing your heart is death.
極めど儚い 偶像の寵児
Frail and fleeting darlings of the idols,
目には目を剥き 牙を剥け
expose your eyes and bare your fangs.
いつか誰もが 散華なる捨て石
Someday everyone will be a sacrificial scattering flower.
輝け 刹那無限の火花
Shine, the spark of an infinite moment,
乱世に迸る
gushing out in the turbulent world.
SAGA SAGA
何が神の如くか 裁きなどさせない
What is like a god? I won't let anyone judge us.
希望 高らかに 打ち鳴らせ
Ring out hope loudly,
呼吸よりも 生きた証
the proof of living more than breathing.
唸れ徒花 朽ち果てても進め
Roar, fruitless flowers; move forward even if you rot.
奪わせはしない 尊厳の愚弄に
I won't let them take it, the mockery of dignity.
飢餓を解き放て
Unleash the starvation.
枯れても走ることを命と呼べ
Call the act of running even when withered 'life'.
空に叫ぶ 脱・生存の定義
Shout to the sky, the definition of escape and survival.
骨を斬らせて 闇を断て
Let your bones be cut, and sever the darkness.
雲間に光る 簒奪의 勝機
The chance for usurpation shining through the clouds,
覚悟を 宿命に突きつけて
push your resolve against fate.
荒野を駆ける 乱世に挑む
Running through the wasteland, challenging the turbulent world.
天下に狂い咲く
Blooming wildly under the heavens.
SAGA SAGA
寄り添う二人に 君がオーバーラップ
As you overlap with the two people close together,
色なき風に 思い馳せて
Sending my thoughts on the colorless wind,
触れた手の温もり今も
the warmth of our touching hands, even now...
Stop 時間を止めて
Stop, and make time stand still.
そういつの日だって
Yes, no matter what day it is,
君の言葉忘れないの
I won't forget your words.
会いたい時に会えない
When I want to see you, I can't.
切なくて もどかしい
It's painful and so frustrating.
から紅に染まる渡月橋
Togetsu Bridge stained in deep crimson,
導かれる日願って
praying for the day I am led to you.
川の流れに祈りを込めて
Putting my prayers into the river's flow,
I've been thinking about you
いつも こころ 君のそば
Always, my heart is by your side.
いにしえの景色 変わりなく
The ancient scenery remains unchanged,
今この瞳に映し出す
reflected in these eyes right now.
彩りゆく季節越えて
Beyond the seasons as they color,
Stock 覚えてますか
Stock, do you remember?
ねぇ いつになったら
Hey, when will it be
また 巡り会えるのかな
that we can meet again?
会いたい時に会えない
When I want to see you, I can't.
この胸を焦がすの
It burns deep within my chest.
から紅に水くくる時
When the water is tied in deep crimson,
君との想いつなげて
connecting my feelings with you.
川の流れに祈りを込めて
Putting my prayers into the river's flow,
I've been thinking about you
いつも 君を探してる
Always, I'm searching for you.
君となら 不安さえ
When I'm with you, even my anxiety
どんな時も消えていくよ
disappears at any moment.
いつになったら優しく
When will I be able
抱きしめられるのかな
to be held gently by you?
から紅の紅葉達さえ
Even the deep crimson autumn leaves
熱い思いを告げては
declare their ardent thoughts,
ゆらり揺れて歌っています
swaying gently as they sing.
I've been thinking about you
いつも いつも 君想ふ
Always, always thinking of you.
はい！ということで、ここまでどうでしたでしょうか？
Alright! So, how was it up to this point?
いやーもう、数多くのゲストに出ていただいて、もう余は本当に嬉しいです。
Wow, so many guests appeared, and I'm truly happy.
本当に、今回のライブは最初にも言ったんですけど、
Truly, as I said at the beginning of this live,
ちょっと和風な感じでまとめさせていただいたので、
I put it together with a Japanese-style feel.
曲も、もうほぼほぼ全部和風っぽい感じで、
With almost all the songs being Japanese-style,
雰囲気をひとつに統一してライブを作らせていただきました。
I created this live with a unified atmosphere.
そしてみんな気づいたかな？ちょっと歌ってる最中ちょっと気づきましたこれ？
And did everyone notice? Did you notice this while I was singing?
おっ！気づきました？新しいマイクなんですよ！すごいでしょ！
Oh! You noticed? It's a new microphone! Isn't it great?
すごいっしょ。え、見て見て。このちょっと、わかりますか？このおなかの柄と...
It's amazing, right? Hey, look, look. Can you see this pattern on the stomach...
ちょっと、お揃いなんですよ。
It's a matching set.
ちょっとこっちも。顔...あ、見えるかな？
Also over here. My face... oh, can you see it?
見える？
Can you see?
ほら、え、めっちゃ可愛いでしょう、これ！
Look, eh, isn't it super cute!
イェーイ！
Yay!
これ、新しいマイク。
This is the new microphone.
あ、ここもね、飾りも付いてるんですよ、この鈴と...
Ah, this part too, it has decorations, these bells and...
この紐もね、付いてて可愛いでしょう！
this cord too, isn't it cute!
イェーイ！
Yay!
これもね、おニューです。
This is also brand new.
やったー！
Hooray!
はい、ということで...
Alright, so...
今回ですね、まだサプライズが残っております！
this time, there's still a surprise left!
ですが...
But...
その前に、ちょっとここで告知をさせていただこうかなと思います！
before that, I'd like to make an announcement!
それでは、告知...
Now then, the announcement...
ドドン！
Tada!
百鬼あやめ 活動7周年記念
Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary
百鬼あやめ活動7周年記念グッズー！
Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary Commemorative Goods!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、ということで、最初はこちら！
Okay, so first up is this!
卓上屏風です！
It's a desk screen!
めっちゃ可愛いでしょう、すごいでしょ！
Isn't it super cute? It's amazing!
デスクに立てて飾れるサイズの屏風となっております。
It's a screen you can stand up on your desk.
こちらはですね、我美蘭先生の描き下ろしの...
This one has an illustration by Gabiran-sensei...
本日着ている新衣装と同じです！
It's the same as the new outfit I'm wearing!
同じ屏風をね、ちょっと飾ってくださいね、みんな。
Please display the same screen, everyone.
はい！
Yes!
可愛いでしょう！
Isn't it cute?
このね、ステージも、背景のステージも...
This stage, and the background stage...
ちょっとそれっぽい感じに合わせていただきました。
were made to match it a bit.
可愛い！
Cute!
続いて、こちら！
Next, this!
湯呑となっております！
It's a teacup!
こちらは三川あゆむ先生に描き下ろしいただいた...
This was drawn by Mikawa Ayumu-sensei...
ぽよよんに乗ったですね、今回も...
me riding on Poyoyon, and this time too...
こちらの新衣装で乗ったよが...
Yo riding in this new outfit...
ミニキャラで描かれた湯呑となっております！
as a mini-character on this teacup!
可愛いでしょう、こうやって乗ってます。
Isn't it cute? I'm riding it like this.
乗ってます。
Riding it.
はい。
Yes.
可愛いでしょう！
Isn't it cute?
そして、続いてはこちら！
And next is this!
こちら、扇子となっております！
This is a folding fan!
こちらはですね、お気づきですか？
Did you notice?
こちらもそうです！
This is also...
新衣装と同じ柄の扇子となっております！
a folding fan with the same pattern!
ど真ん中に「余」って入ってるんですけど。
It has "Yo" right in the middle.
こちら、入れるかすごい迷いました。
I really hesitated about whether to put this in.
「余」を入れようかな、どうしようかな、と話し合って...
I discussed whether to include "Yo" or not...
こちらになりました！
and it ended up like this!
この「余」の右、左で...
To the right and left of "Yo"...
この「余」の、これかな？
this "Yo"... this part?
この振袖と同じ、こっちの色とこっちの色で...
same as the sleeves, with these colors...
ちょっと新衣装っぽい感じにさせていただきました。
I made it feel like the new outfit.
そして、そして、続いてはこちら！
And next is this!
こちら！
This one!
卓上ライトとなっております！
It's a desk light!
行灯風の卓上ライトで、新衣装に合わせた...
It's a lantern-style light, matching the outfit...
和風のデザインとなっております。
with a Japanese-style design.
ぜひ和風っぽい風情あるお部屋タイムを過ごして...
I want you to enjoy some Japanese atmosphere...
ちょっと和風寄りのライトにさせていただきました。
so I chose this Japanese-style light.
可愛いでしょう、これ！
Isn't it cute!
いいよね！
It's good, right?
めっちゃ考えました、こちら。
I put a lot of thought into this.
おすすめです。
I recommend it.
はい。
Yes.
はい、続いてはこちら！
Okay, next is this!
こちらですね！
This one!
お馴染み、販売ボイス。
The usual sales voice.
タイトルは「新衣装でデート」ということで...
The title is "Date in a New Outfit"...
内容は新衣装の余と、水辺で...
and the content is a date with me by the water...
え、水辺？
Eh, by the water?
で、デート？
A date?
で、デートしている内容となっております。
It's about having a date.
まあ、ステージにもね、後ろに水辺がありますけども。
The stage also has a waterfront behind me.
はい。
Yes.
はい、そしてそして...
Okay, and and...
フルセットを購入の方はこちらです！
For those who buy the full set, it's this!
数量限定バージョンは...
The limited version...
直筆サイン＆箔押しメッセージ入りのポストカード！
is a signed postcard with a foil message!
可愛い！
Cute!
通常バージョンは、箔押し複製サインと...
The regular version has a foil signature and...
メッセージ入りの描き下ろしポストカードです。
message on an illustrated postcard.
さらに褒められて喜んでいる余の特典ボイスが...
Plus, a bonus voice of me being happy...
付いてきますね。
that comes with it.
タイトル「またデートしようね」という...何なんだと。
"Let's go on a date again"... What even is that?
まあ、気になる方はぜひ聞いていただければ。
Well, please listen to it if you're interested.
まあ、恥ずかしいので、ここら辺にしておきます。
Well, it's embarrassing, so I'll stop here.
はい、ということで以上...
Okay, so that's all for...
百鬼あやめ活動7周年記念グッズでした！
the 7th Anniversary Commemorative Goods!
みんな、買ってね、よろしくお願いします！
Everyone, please buy them! Thank you!
と、いうことなんですけど...
And that's that, but...
こちら、まだ終わってません！
this isn't over yet!
まだチャンネルはそのままで、頼む！
Don't change the channel yet, please!
そろそろサプライズをね...
It's about time for the surprise...
みんな気になってると思うんで、行っちゃおうかな！
I'm sure you're all curious, so let's go!
みんな気になるよね！
You're all curious, right?
気になる、気になる。
Curious, curious.
うう、そうですよね。
Ooh, right.
と、その前に！
But before that!
このステージ、上へ参ります！
This stage is going up!
ぐんぐんぐん...わあ、上がってる！
Going up, up, up... Wow, it's going up!
みんな見て、すごいでしょ！
Everyone look, isn't it amazing!
みんな見てる？見えてる？
Is everyone watching? Can you see?
みんな見て、ステージも、余も見て！
Everyone look, look at the stage and me!
はい、ということで...
Okay, so...
こちら、上に上がってきたんですけれども
I've come up here...
まぁ上でね、何をやるのかと
And as for what I'll be doing up here...
まぁ薄々ちょっと、気づいてるんじゃないかなとは
Well, I think you might have a slight idea...
まぁ、思うんですけれども
...is what I'm thinking.
何か分かるかな？
Do you know what it is?
みんな教えて教えて教えて
Everyone, tell me, tell me, tell me!
みんな何だと思う？
What do you all think it is?
何だと思う？
What do you think?
お、もちろんほら私、お、当たってますね、なんと！
Oh, of course, look at me! Oh, you're right! And—
はい、こちら！
Yes, here it is!
なんとこちらです！
It's actually this!
ドドン！
Ta-da!
新曲『花吹雪』でーす！やったー！
It's my new song, 'Hanafubuki'! Yay!
花吹雪 HANAFUBUKI / 2025.09.04 Release
Hanafubuki / 2025.09.04 Release
いやぁもうだいぶ長らくお待たせしたと思うんですけれども
I think I've kept you waiting for quite a while,
余様のオリジナル曲の新しいのはいつだ？みたいなね
waiting and asking, 'When's the new original song?'
感じで待っていたかと思うんですけれども
I imagine that's how you've been feeling,
えーこちら、えー作詞・作曲Vellさんに書いていただきました
well, this song was written and composed by Vell-san.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
テーマはですね、可憐な歌声×和風ロック
The theme is 'Lovely Vocals x Japanese-style Rock'.
可愛いだけじゃない、一味違うオリジナルソングとなっております
It's an original song that's more than just cute.
はい、このね、こう綺麗な可憐で重厚な和風ロックとなっておりますので
Yes, it's a beautiful, lovely, yet heavy rock song,
メロディとかね、歌詞もこだわり抜いて磨き上げていただいた楽曲となっておりますので
so the melody and lyrics have been polished with care.
ぜひぜひ皆さん、聴いてください
So everyone, please, please give it a listen.
9月4日0時から、本日の0時からですね
From September 4th at midnight—tonight at midnight—
各種音楽サイトでリリースされるのでぜひ聴いてください
it'll be out on music sites, so please check it out.
聴いてね！いっぱい聴いてね！
Listen to it! Listen to it a lot!
はい、それでは皆さん、大変長らくお待たせいたしました
Alright then, everyone, thank you for waiting.
最後はこの新曲『花吹雪』で送らせていただきたいと思います
I'd like to end with my new song, 'Hanafubuki'.
感想などもね、この衣装もステージと一緒にポストしてください
Please post your thoughts on the outfit and stage.
たくさんポストしてね！
Post a lot, okay!
最後にはですね、メン限パートでちょっと衣装のお写真になったり
Finally, in the members-only part, I'll show photos,
詳しい感じのお話もしたり、ミニライブもありますので
talk more about it, and have a mini-live,
そちらの方もぜひぜひ見に来てくれたら嬉しいです
so I'd be happy if you came to watch that too.
はい、それでは聴いてください
Alright then, please listen.
『花吹雪』
'Hanafubuki'.
共に散る
To scatter together...
宿命なら
if that is our fate,
派手に散りましょう
let's scatter grandly.
花吹雪
Hanafubuki (Storm of Blossoms)
ひらひら舞い落ちる空
Fluttering and dancing down from the sky,
徒に散った泡沫の夢
a transient dream that scattered in vain.
千の華は麗しく咲く
A thousand flowers bloom beautifully,
叶う逢瀬は刹那
the tryst we fulfill is but a moment.
艶やかに舞り
Dancing glamorously,
蝶の儚き命
the ephemeral life of a butterfly.
するり堕ちる今宵は何処
Slipping and falling, where is tonight?
天つ風揺れる
The heavenly wind sways.
狂おしく今咲き誇れ
Bloom proudly now, almost maddeningly.
共に散る
To scatter together...
宿命なら
if that is our fate,
光満ちた舞台ではない
not on a stage filled with light.
闇を裂く旋律は
The melody that tears through the darkness,
ゆらりと香る
fragrant and swaying.
夢を咲かせましょう
Let's make the dream bloom.
花吹雪
Hanafubuki (Storm of Blossoms)
くらくら燃ゆるは焔
Dizzying and burning is the flame,
遠く咲いた明日の夢
a dream of tomorrow blooming far away.
正か否か惑わずに往こう
Let's go without wondering if it's right or wrong,
過去の痛みを胸に
keeping the pain of the past in our hearts.
誰そ彼に
In the twilight,
祈りをひとつ
a single prayer.
涙の川
The river of tears,
穿つ声響く
pierced by the echoing voice.
慎ましくただ進むだけ
Simply moving forward with humility.
茜さす空の果てで
At the edge of the madder-red sky,
褪せた過去の憧れを見る
I see the faded longings of the past.
澄み渡る静寂に
In the clear stillness,
未来を繋ぐ
connecting to the future.
答え求むれど
Searching for an answer,
にべも無し
but finding no sign of one.
共に散る宿命なら
If it is fate to scatter together,
光満ちた舞台で笑え
Smile on the stage filled with light.
闇を裂く
Tearing through the darkness,
旋律は
the melody...
ゆらりと薫る
sways and scents.
夢を咲かせましょう
Let us make our dreams bloom,
花吹雪
a flower blizzard.
7周年ライブ見てくれてありがとう！！
Thank you for watching the 7th anniversary live!!
新衣装にキレイなステージどうだったかな！？
How did you like the new outfit and beautiful stage!?
みんなが少しでも笑顔になってくれたら嬉しいです！！
I'd be happy if it made you smile even just a little!!
8年目もよろしくね～～！！！！！
百鬼あやめ
Please support me in my 8th year too~~!!!!!
- Nakiri Ayame